Guide to the Mexico Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Visual, Circa 1865-1911; Part II. V
  - Lithographs, drawings, illustrations, engravings and prints
    - Portraits, individuals
      - Sánchez de Tagle, Francisco Manuel, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 12, Reel 31)
      - Santibáñez, Manuel, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 12, Reel 31)
      - Satorio, José Manuel, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 12, Reel 31)
      - Scott, Winfield, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 12, Reel 31)
      - Taylor, Zachary, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 12, Reel 31)
      - Terán, Jesus, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 12, Reel 31)
      - Tornel y Mendivil, José María, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 12, Reel 31)
      - Treviño, G, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 12, Reel 31)
      - Vega, Placido, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 12, Reel 31)
      - Vélez, Francisco, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 12, Reel 31)
      - Zuloaga, Félix, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 12, Reel 31)
      - Zúñiga y Azevedo, Gaspar, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 12, Reel 31)
      - Unidentified, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 13, Reel 31)
    - Portraits, group
      - "Barretero", [18--] (Box 70, Folder 14, Reel 31)
      - "Constitución..." [six portraits including Benito Juárez and other prominent Mexican leaders associated with the 1857 constitution] (Box 70, Folder 14, Reel 31)
      - "Fumadores de Opio", [18--] (Box 70, Folder 14, Reel 31)
      - Group of acrobats, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 14, Reel 31)
      - "Paso del Río", [18--] (Box 70, Folder 14, Reel 31)
    - Portraits, series
      - Artists
        - León, Tomás, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Morales, Melesio, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Gottschalk, L. M, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Meyerbeer, G, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Castelar, E, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Balderas, Agustín, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Zamacois, Elisa de, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Salvatierra, Juan P, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Cadena, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Palou, José, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Arguimbau, Lorenzo, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Dioesni, Romeo, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Leonardi, Emilia, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Marchetti, F, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Ortega, Aniceto, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Vázquez, Gerónimo, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Gómez, José Antonio, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
        - Ituarte, Julio, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 15, Reel 31)
      - "Mujeres célebres" [celebrated women]
        - Adosinda, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Aragon, Petronila de, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Castilla, Leonor, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Castro, Inés del, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Egilona, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Elvira (Doña), [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Gimena (wife of El Cid), [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Guzmán y la Cerda (Doctora), [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - María Pita, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Navarra, Blanca de, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Perelada, Mercadera de, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Plotina, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Sancha (wife of Ferdinand the Great, Fernando el mago), [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Santa Marta, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Teresa, Infanta de León, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Urraca Fernández, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Velasquita, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
        - Zaida (wife of Alfonso VI), [18--] (Box 70, Folder 16, Reel 31)
      - Spanish priests and noblemen
        - Hidalgo, Doctor Bartolomé, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 17, Reel 31)
        - Mata, Licenciado Fernando de, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 17, Reel 31)
        - Pineda, El Padre Ivan de, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 17, Reel 31)
        - Valderrama, Fray Pedro de, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 17, Reel 31)
        - Vera Bustos, Antonio de, [18--] (Box 70, Folder 17, Reel 31)
  - Photographs
    - Columbus monument, [18--] (Box 71, Folder 18, Reel 32)
    - Francisco Madero
      - "Feb. 9. 1911", 1911 February 9 (Box 71, Folder 19, Reel 32)
      - González, Prov. Gov, 1910-1911 (Box 71, Folder 19, Reel 32)
      - Madero's headquarters, 1910-1911 (Box 71, Folder 19, Reel 32)
      - "Blanco reading proclamation", 1910-1911 (Box 71, Folder 19, Reel 32)
      - Madero's wife, Madero, Frederico Gonzales Garza, 1910-1911 (Box 71, Folder 19, Reel 32)
      - Madero's wife, Francisco Madero, 1910-1911 (Box 71, Folder 19, Reel 32)
      - Group photo including Francisco and Gustavo Madero, and Venustiano Carranza, 1910-1911 (Box 71, Folder 19, Reel 32)
      - Orozco's Father, 1910-1911 (Box 71, Folder 19, Reel 32)
      - Portrait of Francisco I. Madero, 1910-1911 (Box 71, Folder 19, Reel 32)
    - Military
      - "Fusiladores del Emperador Maximiliano,", Circa 1865 (Box 71, Folder 20, Reel 32)
      - Military band, [18--] (Box 71, Folder 20, Reel 32)
    - Portraits
      - Díaz, Porfirio, [18--] (Box 71, Folder 21, Reel 32)
      - Gobernadores, Consejeros y Diputados de Yucatán, 1882-1885 (Box 71, Folder 21, Reel 32)
      - "Leonero de S.L.P.", [18--] (Box 71, Folder 21, Reel 32)
      - "Pulquero", [18--] (Box 71, Folder 21, Reel 32)
    - San Luis Potosí
      - Cathedral, [18--] (Box 71, Folder 22, Reel 32)
      - Convento - Hospital de San Juan de Dios, [18--] (Box 71, Folder 22, Reel 32)
      - Obispado, [18--] (Box 71, Folder 22, Reel 32)
      - Plaza de Armas, [18--] (Box 71, Folder 22, Reel 32)
    - Unidentified buildings, [18--] (Box 71, Folder 23, Reel 32)
    - Unidentified portraits [two have labels of San Luis Potosí photographers], [18--] (Box 71, Folder 24, Reel 32)
    - Photograph albums
      - Title: "Old Mexico, 1895." Places: Mitla, Amencaca, Puebla, Mexico City, León, Cholula, Torreón, Querétaro, Guanajuato, Orizaba, Guadalajara, Tlaxcala, Zacatecas, Guadalupe, Aguascalientes, San Antonio, Galveston, and New Orleans. Description: Bound photograph album with Mayo & Weed, Chicago, embossed on the spine. The album consists of 162 prints showing mountains, parks, plants, beasts of burden, transportation, public buildings, churches, factories, graves, waterfalls, laundries, bullfights, aqueducts, vendors, laborers, individuals and groups, bars, homes, ruins, artifacts, views of cities and towns, markets, religious paintings, street scenes, and scenes from daily life. Some of the photographs are labeled. Some labels are illegible. (Box 72, Folder 25, Reel 32)
      - Title: Unidentified photograph album. Places: Toluca, Cuantitlán, Tenancingo, Chalco, Teotihucan, Chalmo, Ecatepec and Calimaya. Description: Fourteen photographs with the following captions: "1. Cevercería de Graf - (Toluca)" "2. Cruz de Cuantitlán" "3. Arquería de Tlalmanalco (D. de Chalco)" "4. Palacio Municipal de Tenancingo" "5. Ruinas de la casa de Sor Juana Inés de la Cruz (Chalco) "6. Pirámides de S. Juan Tiotehuacán (Distrito de Oyumba)" "7. Santuario de Chalmo" "8. Interior de Templo del Calvario de Tenancingo" "9. Arquería de Citio" "10. Casa donde se fusiló á Morelos en Ecatepec (D. de Zumpango)" "11. Acordada de Toluca" "12. Calvario de Tenancingo" "13. Palacio Municipal de Calimaya (D. de Tenango)" "14. Vista general de Toluca,", undated (Box 73, Folder 26, Reel 32)
- Oversize, Circa 1865-1911
  - Title: Viceregal decree, 1797 (Box 74, Folder 1, Reel 33)
  - Title: Royal decree, 1798-1799 (Box 74, Folder 2, Reel 33)
  - Title: Band from the Commander of the Provincias Internas, 1800 (Box 74, Folder 3, Reel 33)
  - Title: Publication of a decree from the Commandant of the Provincias Internas, 1800-1801 (Box 74, Folder 4, Reel 33)
  - Title: Hand drawn map, circa 1810-1821 (Box 74, Folder 5, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Don Antonio Cordero y Bustamente Coronel de caballeria por S.M....", 1811 (Box 74, Folder 6, Reel 33)
  - Title: Decree by Agustín Itúrbide, 1814 October 29 (Box 74, Folder 7, Reel 33)
  - Title: Decree for public safety, 1816 August 4 (Box 74, Folder 8, Reel 33)
  - Title: Decree by the Commandant of San Luis Potosí, 1816 August 7 (Box 74, Folder 9, Reel 33)
  - Title: "El Commandante General a los americanos de Tehuacan a los pueblos de la costa sotavento.", 1816 September 14 (Box 74, Folder 10, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Comiciones del h. congreso y diputados que la componen.", 1824 April 28 (Box 74, Folder 11, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Plan que manifiesta el numero de habitantes....", Circa 1825 (Box 74, Folder 12, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Presupuerto de la Tesorería General....", 1827 January 3 (Box 74, Folder 13, Reel 33)
  - Title: Modelo de padrón, 1841 March 8 (Box 74, Folder 14, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official proclamation, 1843 February 7 (Box 74, Folder 15, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1843 February 10 (Box 74, Folder 16, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1844 March 5 (Box 74, Folder 17, Reel 33)
  - Title: Proclamation of retirement, 1844 March 30 (Box 74, Folder 18, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1844 April 17 (Box 74, Folder 19, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1845 May 14 (Box 74, Folder 20, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1846 August 1 (Box 74, Folder 21, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1846 August 19 (Box 74, Folder 22, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1846 August 19 (Box 74, Folder 23, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1846 December 18 (Box 74, Folder 24, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1847 September 12 (Box 74, Folder 25, Reel 33)
  - Title: Confirmation of appointment, 1848 October 31 (Box 74, Folder 26, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Certificate of constancy.", 1851 March 12 (Box 74, Folder 27, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1852 January 14 (Box 74, Folder 28, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1853 March 14 (Box 74, Folder 29, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1853 August 10 (Box 74, Folder 30, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1853 August 11 (Box 74, Folder 31, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1853 August 26 (Box 74, Folder 32, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1856 April 14 (Box 74, Folder 33, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official promotion, 1856 December 11 (Box 74, Folder 34, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Carta de seguridad.", 1857 May 12 (Box 74, Folder 35, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Manuel G. Aguirre, Prefecto político de México a sus habitantes....", 1863 August 12 (Box 74, Folder 36, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1866 February 5 (Box 74, Folder 37, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1866 April 26 (Box 74, Folder 38, Reel 33)
  - Title: Patent grant, 1866 June 11 (Box 74, Folder 39, Reel 33)
  - Title: "El Prefecto Político del Departamento del Valle de Mexico, a los habitantes....", 1866 (Box 74, Folder 40, Reel 33)
  - Title: Appointment, 1867 January 2 (Box 74, Folder 41, Reel 33)
  - Title: Execution order, 1867 June 14 (Box 74, Folder 42, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1867 October 12 (Box 74, Folder 43, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1868 July 1 (Box 74, Folder 44, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1870 October 1 (Box 74, Folder 45, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1874 March 2 (Box 74, Folder 46, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1881 February 21 (Box 74, Folder 47, Reel 33)
  - Title: Official appointment, 1885 May 22 (Box 74, Folder 48, Reel 33)
  - Title: Genealogical chart., [18--] (Box 74, Folder 49, Reel 33)
  - Title: "América septentrional yndependiente.", [17--?] (Box 75, Folder 50, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Descripción ignografíca de las dimensiones....", [17--?] (Box 75, Folder 51, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Don Félix María Calleja del rey....", 1811 May 3 (Box 75, Folder 52, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Don Miguel Hidalgo y Costilla y don Ignacio Allende generalísimo de America.", 1811 June 18 (Box 75, Folder 53, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Don Facundo Melgares capitán de armas en esta villa por el superior govierno.", Circa 1811 (Box 75, Folder 54, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Población de México....", 1812 February 26 (Box 75, Folder 55, Reel 33)
  - Title: "El supremo congreso nacional gubernativo de estos dominos.", 1814 May 14 (Box 75, Folder 56, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Don Manuel Jacinto de Acevedo intendente corregidor de esta provincia....", 1820 May 4 (Box 75, Folder 57, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Plan estadístico que manisfiesta la situación de la ciudad....", 1828 July 22 (Box 75, Folder 58, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Noticia que manifiesta el número de escuelas de primeras letras que hay en el Distrito de Tancanhuitz....", 1838 July 11 (Box 75, Folder 59, Reel 33)
  - Title: Francisco Pacheco collection, 1842-1853 (Box 75, Folder 60, Reel 33)
  - Title: Pascual Martínez de Castro sus servicios a la nación, 1846-1861 (Box 75, Folder 61, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Resumen general de los cargos y datos...", 1854 January 1 (Box 75, Folder 62, Reel 33)
  - Title: "José del Villar y Bocanegra, Prefecto Político del Departmento del Valle de México....", 1863 December 29 (Box 75, Folder 63, Reel 33)
  - Title: Grant of exclusive right of patent, 1894 August 9 (Box 75, Folder 64, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Estado que manifiesta el armamento, correaje y municiones ....", 1907 August 8 (Box 75, Folder 65, Reel 33)
  - Title: Los Debates, 1848 April 13 (Folder 76A, Reel 33)
  - Title: Appointment, 1854 January 2 (Folder 76B, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Pocianno Arriaga, Gobernador del Distrito Federal, a sus habitantes....", 1863 February 3-12 (Folder 76C, Reel 33)
  - Title: Abogados., Circa 1865 (Folder 76D, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Manifiesto.", 1870 September 16 (Folder 76E, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Monitor Republicano and Diario Oficial, 1872 July 23, 25 (Folder 76F, Reel 33)
  - Title: Diario Oficial., circa 1873 (Folder 76G, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Socialista, 1874 February 22 (Folder 76H, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Federalista, 1874 September 16 (Folder 76I, Reel 33)
  - Title: Diario Oficial and La Iberia, 1875 May 16, September 18 (Folder 76J, Reel 33)
  - Title: La Voz de México, 1876 May 7 (Folder 76K, Reel 33)
  - Title: Diario Oficial, 1878 December 27 (Folder 76L, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Monitor Republicano and La Patria, 1881 April 1, September 16 (Folder 76M, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Socialista, 1883 April 28, May 26, June 5 (Folder 76N, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Monitor Republicano, 1885 July 1, 1886 January 31 (Folder 76O, Reel 33)
  - Title: La Jueventud Literaria and El Abogado Cristiano Ilustrado, 1887 July 17, 1888 July 18 (Folder 76P, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Monitor del Pueblo, 1889 September 15-16 (Folder 76Q, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Mundo and El Universal, 1890 July 17, 19 (Folder 76R, Reel 33)
  - Title: Revista de México, 1891 February 8 (Folder 76S, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Monitor Republicano, El Universal and El Nacional, 1893 May 17-18, October 8 (Folder 76T, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Universal, 1894 September 16 (Folder 76U, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Noticioso, El Universal, and El Siglo Diez y Nueve, 1895 July 30 (Folder 76V, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Universal, El Democracia, and El Noticioso, 1895 July 31 (Folder 76W, Reel 33)
  - Title: Gilbas, 1895 July 31, August 1-2 (Folder 76X, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Nacional and Gilbas, 1895 August 5, 8 (Folder 76Y, Reel 33)
  - Title: El Imparcial and El Pais, 1900 September 16, 1908 October 4 (Folder 76Z, Reel 33)
  - Title: Boletín Municipal, 1907 May 1 (Folder 76AA, Reel 33)
  - Title: Hidalgo facsimile newspaper., undated (Folder 76BB, Reel 33)
  - Title: "Lista general de los Soldados de esta Ciudad que andan en campaña con expresión del dia de su salida dep punto para donde, 1862 February 4-July 22 (Folder 76CC, Reel 33)
- Additional material, Accession 2006-M-021; 2
  - Personnel, résumés
    - Oaxaca, Undated (Box 1)
    - Acapulco, Undated (Box 1)
    - Puebla, Undated (Box 1)
    - Morelos, Undated (Box 1)
    - Guanajuato, Undated (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1749-1868; Accession 2013-M-025
  This accession consists of maps and published illustrations related to Mexico, including scenes of various Mexican cities, the war with France, and silver mining.
  - Maps
    - Description: Map of the Gulf of Amapalla, Mexico. Cartographer: Unknown. Publisher: Unknown, 1749 (Box 1)
    - Description: Map of the capital of old Mexico/Carte du Lac de Mexico et de ses Environs, from l'Histoire générale des voyages. Cartographer: Jacques Nicholas Bellin. Publisher: Unknown., 1754 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Vue de l'Entrée de Chequetan ou Seguataneo, restant au N.E. à la distance de 5 Milles," "Gezigt van den Ingang van de Haven van Acapulco." Cartographer: Schley. Publisher: Unknown., 1761 (Box 1)
    - Description: Map of Mexico City. Cartographer: Unknown. Publisher: Unknown, 1895 (Box 1)
  - Published illustrations
    - Title: "View of the Port of Acapulco, Mexico." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: Cassell's Illustrated, page 272., 1856 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Sketch in the Market-Place of Santa Lucia." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 556., 1858 June 5 (Box 1)
    - Title: "La Citta' Di Messico A Volo D'Uccello." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: Unknown., Circa 1860 (Box 1)
    - Title: "La place d'armes, à Mexico." Illustrator: Godefroi Durand. Publication: L'Universel, page 180., Circa 1860 (Box 1)
    - Title: "La vallée de Mexico, prise des hauteurs de Chapultepec." Illustrator: K. Rouague. Publication: L'Universel, page 196., Circa 1860 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Vue Générale d'Orizaba--Campement du corps expéditionnaire du Mexique." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: L'Universel, page 244., Circa 1860 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Dames Mexicaines," "Mexico--Promenade de Bucareli." Illustrators: Unknown. Publication: L'Universel, page 264., Circa 1860 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Vue de la Vera-Cruz (Mexique), òu se sont donné rendez-vous les flottes française(s), anglaise(s) et espagnole(s)." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, page 808., 1861 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Expédition Du Mexique--La ville de Guanajato, occupée part les troupes françaises (Vue prise des hauteurs du Serro-San-Miguel)." Illustrator: Bertrand. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, page 205., 1862 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Vue de la ville et de la rade d'Acapulco, occupées par les troupes françaises," "Expédition du Mexique--Une compagnie du 1st bataillon de chasseurs à pied disperse un corps de partisans à Jerez." Illustrators: Unknown, E. Roevens. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, page 324., 1862 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Vue générale de la ville de Queretaro, prise de la route de Mexico, occupé par les troupes françaises," "La colonne du général Douay arrivant à San-Juan del Rio, par les hauteurs dominant la ville du côté de Mexico." Illustrator: Bertrand. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, page 72., 1862 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The Intervention in Mexico: Fort San Juan D'Ulloa, Vera Cruz." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 134., 1862 February 1 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Town and Port of Acapulco, on the West Coast of Mexico, with the English and French Squadron Lying in the Harbour." The Illustrated London News., 1862 July 12 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Expédition du Mexique--Vue générale de Jalapa." Illustrator: A. Neroy. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, page 245., 1863 (Box 1)
    - Title: Expédition du Mexique--Vue de la ville de Matamoras." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, page 256., 1863 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Expédition du Mexique--Vue générale de Zacatecaz." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, page 165., 1863 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Mexique--Types de chefs partisans de Juarez, tenant la campagne," "Expédition Du Mexique--Vue de la ville de Real el Monte, située à 1000 mètres au-dessus du niveau de la mer." Illustrators: Unknown. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, page 268., 1863 (Box 1)
    - Title: Expédition du Mexique "Occupation de la ville de Tampico par l'escadre, sous les ordres du commandant en chef des forces navales françaises dans le golfe du Mexique." Illustrator: E. Roevens. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, page 216., 1863 (Box 1)
    - Description: Several small illustrations of government buildings, churches, and monuments in Mexico. Illustrators: Unknown. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, pages 104-105, 1863 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Vue à vol d'oiseau de la ville de Mexico, rendue au Français." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: Le Monde Illustré, page 44., 1863 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Panorama of the City of Mexico." From photographs of M. Edouard Charnay. Illustrator: W. Thomas. Publication: The Illustrated London News, pages 64-65., 1863 January 17 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Plan of Puebla." Illustrator: J. Dower. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 657, 1863 June 13 (Box 1)
    - Title: "The War in Mexico." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 692., 1863 June 27 (Box 1)
    - Title: "View of Matamoras, Mexico, from the South." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 377., 1863 October 10 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Port and Town of Vera Cruz, Mexico." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, page 49., 1867 July 13 (Box 1)
    - Title: "Conveying Silver from the Mines to Mexico." Illustrator: Unknown. Publication: The Illustrated London News, paged 352., 1868 April 11 (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1952-1995; Accession 2015-M-051
  This accession consists of late twentieth-century imprints on various trade unions in Mexico. The bulk of the materials comes from the period between 1980 and 1995. Organizations involved include Ford, Volkswagen, Petróleos Mexicanos (PEMEX), Confederación de Trabajadores de México (CTM), Sindicato de Telefonistas de la República Mexicana (STRM), Sindicato Mexicano de Electricistas (SME), and Confederación Revolucionaria de Obreros y Campesinos (CROC). Materials consist of directories, contracts, labor agreements, salary agreements, retirement issues, press releases, and other official union documents.
  - Automobile Industry
    - Ford, 1985-1995
      - Contracts I, 1989-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Contracts II, 1992-1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - General articles, 1990-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Volkswagen
      - General I, 1989-1992 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - General II, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Confederación de Trabajadores de México
    - General I, 1986-1992 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - General II, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Petroleum Industry - PEMEX, 1980-1994
    - General, 1989-1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Official documents, 1980-1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Speeches, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Sindicato de Telefonistas de la República Mexicana, 1988-1995
    - General I, 1990-1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - General II, 1988-1994 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Productivity, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Sindicato Mexicano de Electricistas, 1990-1994
    - General, 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Contact 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Confederación Revolucionaria de Obreros y Campesinos, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 6)